Guide to the James Kirkup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1938-2007; Series II; 54.42; (135 boxes)
  - Drama, Opera and Music
    - The Magic Drum
      - Proofs, corrected, undated (Box 131, Folder 1232)
      - Reviews and ephemera, 1970-1977 (Box 131, Folder 1233-1238)
    - Mr. Pickwick!, A comedy opera, typescript, undated (Box 132, Folder 1239)
    - My Brother Vincent by Marianne Helweg and James Kirkup, typescript (copy) and related correspondence, 1952, undated (Box 132, Folder 1240)
    - Not on Speaking Terms, draft, typescript and related material, 1970s (Box 132, Folder 1241)
    - The Peach Garden, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 132, Folder 1242-1243)
    - The Pot of Poison, typescript (copy), undated
    - "Religious Dramas," (Various titles), notes and drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 132, Folder 1244)
    - Scene for a semi-secular miracle, holograph, undated (Box 132, Folder 1245)
    - The Silken Drum (libretto), draft and notes, typescript and holograph, 1984, undated (Box 132, Folder 1246-1247)
    - Translation, "Fake TV Script," typescript, 1974 (Box 132, Folder 1248)
    - The Triumph of Harmony, typescript, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 1249)
    - Two Pigeons Flying High, typescript, 1955 (Box 133, Folder 1250)
    - Upon This Rock, holograph and typescript, 1955, undated (Box 133, Folder 1251-1252)
    - The Wakefield Mysteries, typescript, undated (Box 133, Folder 1253)
    - [Various titles], music with words by James Kirkup, printed versions and related correspondence, 1950s-1970s (Box 133, Folder 1254)
  - Obituaries by James Kirkup
    Obituaries are organized under two headings: Alphabetical Files and Chronological Files.
    - Alphabetical Files
      - Abe-Kinnosuke, notes and clippings, 1990s, 2007 (Box 134, Folder 1255-1322)
      - Levinas-Yupanqui, notes and clippings, 1990s, 2007 (Box 135, Folder 1323-1359)
    - Chronological Files
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, notes and clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 136, Folder 1360-1365)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, notes and clippings, 1991-1998 (Box 137, Folder 1366-1372)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup in The Independent, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1992-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1373)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 138, Folder 1374-1382)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings (continued, 1998-2000 (Box 139, Folder 1383-1386)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 139, Folder 1387-1391)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 2002-2003 (Box 140, Folder 1392-1393)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 2002-2004 (Box 140, Folder 1394-1402)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings (continued), 2002-2004 (Box 141, Folder 1403-1405)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 2004 April (Box 141, Folder 1406-1407)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings (continued), 2004 April (Box 142, Folder 1408-1409)
      - Obituaries by James Kirkup, drafts and clippings, 2006 (Box 142, Folder 1410)
  - Notebooks
    - "2 Old Notebooks", 1936-1937; 2 notebooks (Box 143, Folder 1411)
    - Notebooks, 1938-1939, undated; 3 notebooks (Box 143, Folder 1412)
    - Notebooks: Journals, Douai, 1939; 2 notebooks (Box 143, Folder 1413)
    - Notebook: "Early Attempts At French Poetry", 1939? (Box 143, Folder 1414)
    - Notebook: "The Delivered Lovers" and other poems, 1943 (Box 143, Folder 1415)
    - Notebook: "Work book", 1943 (Box 143, Folder 1416)
    - Notebook: "Dead Gardener, Elegy, etc.", 1944 (Box 143, Folder 1417)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1946 November (Box 143, Folder 1418)
    - Notebook: Minchenden Grammar School. Southgate, London, 1947-1948 (Box 143, Folder 1419)
    - Notebook: Poems, 1948? (Box 144, Folder 1420)
    - Notebooks: Poetry, 1948?; 2 notebooks (Box 144, Folder 1421)
    - Notebook: Poems, short stories, 1949 (Box 144, Folder 1422)
    - Notebook: Spanish vocabulary and outline for play or novel, 1950s (Box 144, Folder 1423)
    - Notebook: Poetry, 1950 (Box 144, Folder 1424)
    - Notebook: Address Book, 1951 (Box 144, Folder 1425)
    - Notebook: "Work Book", 1952 (Box 144, Folder 1426)
    - Notebook: Calendar, 1953 (Box 144, Folder 1427)
    - Notebook: Diaries, 1954 (Box 144, Folder 1428)
    - Notebook: Poems and songs, 1954 (Box 144, Folder 1429)
    - Notebook: "Book List", 1955 (Box 145, Folder 1430)
    - Notebook, including poems and The True Mystery of the Nativity, draft of translation, 1955 (Box 145, Folder 1431)
    - Notebook: Work Book, 1955 June 5 (Box 145, Folder 1432)
    - Notebook: Bath Academy of Art, 1955-1956 (Box 145, Folder 1433)
    - Notebook: Poetry, 1956 (Box 145, Folder 1434)
    - Notebook: Malayan Journal, Volume One, 1957 October 7-1957 November 23 (Box 145, Folder 1435)
    - Notebook: Journal, "Andrew James", 1958 (Box 145, Folder 1436)
    - Notebook: Malayan Journal Volume 2, 1961-1962 (Box 145, Folder 1437)
    - Notebook: Malayan Journal Volume 3, 1962 (Box 145, Folder 1438)
    - Notebook: Journal "4", 1962? (Box 145, Folder 1439)
    - Notebook: Poems, 1962 (Box 146, Folder 1440)
    - Notebook: Tokyo, 1963 (Box 146, Folder 1441)
    - Diaries, 1965; 2 notebooks (Box 146, Folder 1442)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1965 (Box 146, Folder 1443)
    - Notebook: Journal, Osaka-Fukui, 1965 (Box 146, Folder 1444)
    - Notebook: Poems, 1969 (Box 146, Folder 1445)
    - Notebook: Journal, Amherst to San Francisco, 1969-1970 (Box 146, Folder 1446)
    - Notebook: "A book of aphorisms and one-line poems," Nagoya, 1971 (Box 146, Folder 1447)
    - Notebook: Journal, "Depart by 'wagon' for our great trip around Kyushu...", 1971 (Box 146, Folder 1448)
    - Notebooks: Journals, San Diego, 1971; 2 notebooks (Box 146, Folder 1449)
    - Notebook: Newcastle, Norway, etc., 1972 (Box 146, Folder 1450)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1974 (Box 146, Folder 1451)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1974 (Box 147, Folder 1452)
    - Notebook: Journal ("1"), 1976-1977 (Box 147, Folder 1453)
    - Notebook: Journal ("2"), 1977 (Box 147, Folder 1454)
    - Notebook: Journal ("3"), 1977 (Box 147, Folder 1455)
    - Notebook: Journal ("4"), 1977 (Box 147, Folder 1456)
    - Notebook: Journal ("5"), 1977 (Box 147, Folder 1457)
    - Notebook: Poems, 1977 (Box 147, Folder 1458)
    - Notebook: Journal ("6"), 1978 (Box 147, Folder 1459)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 1460)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 1461)
    - Notebook: Journal, Paris, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 1462)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 1463)
    - Notebook: "New Poems", 1978 (Box 148, Folder 1464)
      Includes drafts of "Japan Journal."
    - Notebook: Tokyo, 1978 (Box 148, Folder 1465)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1979 (Box 148, Folder 1466)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1979 (Box 148, Folder 1467)
    - Notebook: Journal, Zurich, 1979 (Box 148, Folder 1468)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1979 (Box 148, Folder 1469)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1980 (Box 148, Folder 1470)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1980 (Box 148, Folder 1471)
    - Notebook: Journal "Departure from Europe", 1980 (Box 148, Folder 1472)
    - Notebooks: Journals, 1980; 3 notebooks (Box 148, Folder 1473)
    - Notebook: poems ("Cambridge blue"), 1980 (Box 148, Folder 1474)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1981 (Box 149, Folder 1475)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 1476)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 1477)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 1478)
    - Notebook: Journal, "Awake early to make ready for the flight to Paris...", 1982 (Box 149, Folder 1479)
    - Notebook: Journal, Santa Fe, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 1480)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1983 (Box 149, Folder 1481)
    - Notebook: Journal, San Francisco, 1983 (Box 149, Folder 1482)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1983 (Box 149, Folder 1483)
    - "Robert Walser notebook", 1983, 1994 (Box 149, Folder 1484)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 1485)
    - Notebook: Journal, Zurich, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 1486)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1985 (Box 150, Folder 1487)
    - Notebook: Journal "Providence", 1985 (Box 150, Folder 1488)
    - Notebook: "Projects book", 1985 (Box 150, Folder 1489)
    - Notebook: Journals, 1986; 2 notebooks (Box 150, Folder 1490)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1986 (Box 150, Folder 1491)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1986 (Box 150, Folder 1492)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1986-1987 (Box 150, Folder 1493)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1987 (Box 150, Folder 1494)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 1495)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kyoto, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 1496)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 1497)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1988 (Box 151, Folder 1498)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1988-1989 (Box 151, Folder 1499)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1500)
    - Notebook: Kyoto, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1501)
    - Notebook: "New Poems", 1988-1990 (Box 151, Folder 1502)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1990 (Box 151, Folder 1503)
    - Notebook: Journal, "My 73rd birthday"..., 1991 (Box 151, Folder 1504)
    - Notebook: Akemashite Omedite Gozaymasdu, 1992 (Box 151, Folder 1505)
    - Notebook: Journal, "Almost 30 years since Riette gave me this notebook...", 1992 (Box 151, Folder 1506)
    - Notebooks, 1992-1994; 4 notebooks (Box 151, Folder 1507)
    - Notebook: Journal, London, 1993 (Box 152, Folder 1508)
    - Notebook: "Working notebook", 1994-1995 (Box 152, Folder 1509)
    - Notebook: Journal "1995 February", circa 1995 (Box 152, Folder 1510)
    - Notebook: "New Poems", 1995 (Box 152, Folder 1511)
    - Notebook: Journal "1995 August 14", circa 1995 (Box 152, Folder 1512)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra "1995 October 26", circa 1995 (Box 152, Folder 1513)
    - Notebook: Journal "1995 December 7", circa 1995 (Box 152, Folder 1514)
    - Notebook: Journal "1996 January", circa 1996 (Box 152, Folder 1515)
    - Notebook: Journal "1996 February", circa 1996 (Box 152, Folder 1516)
    - Notebook: Journal, 1996 February 13-April 1 (Box 152, Folder 1517)
    - Notebook: Journal, London "1996 April", circa 1996 (Box 152, Folder 1518)
    - Notebook: Journal, Wakes "1996 July 21", circa 1996 (Box 153, Folder 1519)
    - Notebook: Journal "1996 September 1", circa 1996 (Box 153, Folder 1520)
    - Notebook: Journal "1996 November", circa 1996 (Box 153, Folder 1521)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra "1997 March 18", circa 1997 (Box 153, Folder 1522)
    - Notebook: Journal and Work Book "1997 January 1", circa 1997 (Box 153, Folder 1523)
    - Notebook: Journal "1997 May 16", circa 1997 (Box 153, Folder 1524)
    - Notebook: Journal "1997 August 1", circa 1997 (Box 153, Folder 1525)
    - Notebook: Journal "1997 October 22", circa 1997 (Box 153, Folder 1526)
    - Notebook: Journal "1998 January", circa 1998 (Box 153, Folder 1527)
    - Notebook: Journal "1998 March 17", circa 1998 (Box 154, Folder 1528)
    - Notebook: Journal "1998 April 26", circa 1998 (Box 154, Folder 1529)
    - Notebook: Journal "1998 July 18", circa 1998 (Box 154, Folder 1530)
    - Notebook: Journal "1998 September 23", circa 1998 (Box 154, Folder 1531)
    - Notebook: Journal "1999 January 1", circa 1999 (Box 154, Folder 1532)
    - Notebook: Journal "1999 March", circa 1999 (Box 154, Folder 1533)
    - Notebook: Journal "1999 April 23", circa 1999 (Box 154, Folder 1534)
    - Notebook: Journal, Toulouse "1999 May 4", circa 1999 (Box 154, Folder 1535)
    - Notebook: Journal, Andorra "1999 August 15", circa 1999 (Box 154, Folder 1536)
    - Notebook: Journal "2000 January 1", circa 2000 (Box 155, Folder 1537)
    - Notebook: Journal "2000 April 4", circa 2000 (Box 155, Folder 1538)
    - Notebook: Journal "2000 June 17", circa 2000 (Box 155, Folder 1539)
    - Notebook: Journal "2000 September 13", circa 2000 (Box 155, Folder 1540)
    - Notebook: Journal "2000 November 1" (Box 155, Folder 1541)
    - Notebook: Journal "2001 January 28", circa 2001 (Box 155, Folder 1542)
    - Notebook: Journal "2001 April 14", circa 2001 (Box 155, Folder 1543)
    - Notebook: Journal "2001 June 18", circa 2001 (Box 155, Folder 1544)
    - Notebook: Journal "2002 January 1", circa 2002 (Box 155, Folder 1545)
    - Notebook: Journal "2002 March 29", circa 2002 (Box 156, Folder 1546)
    - Notebook: Journal "2003 January 1", circa 2003 (Box 156, Folder 1547)
    - Notebook: Memo book, undated (Box 156, Folder 1548)
    - Notebook: "An interview with myself", undated (Box 156, Folder 1549)
    - Notebook: "Amherst Notes etc. (poems)", undated (Box 156, Folder 1550)
    - Notebook: "Books etc.", undated (Box 156, Folder 1551)
    - Notebook: "First Steps Abroad...", undated (Box 156, Folder 1552)
    - Notebook: "The Flowers of Discontent or the Privelege of Fantasy, Book the First", undated (Box 156, Folder 1553)
    - Notebook: German, undated (Box 156, Folder 1554)
    - Notebook: German Literature. Upper Sixth, undated (Box 156, Folder 1555)
    - Notebook: "German Vocabulary", undated (Box 156, Folder 1556)
    - Notebook: H. Kirkup. English, undated (Box 156, Folder 1557)
    - Notebook: Japanese in Paris, etc., undated (Box 156, Folder 1558)
    - Notebook: "Memo", June 10 (Box 156, Folder 1559)
    - Notebook: Journal, undated (Box 156, Folder 1560)
    - Notebook: Journal, Denver, January 4 (Box 156, Folder 1561)
    - Notebook: Journal, Kuala Lumpur-Singapore-Manila-Hong Kong-Kobe, March 9-23 (Box 156, Folder 1562)
    - Notebook: Journal, New York, undated (Box 157, Folder 1563)
    - Notebook: Journal " ... on my way to Macao ...", April 16 (Box 157, Folder 1564)
    - Notebook: Journal "Summer", undated (Box 157, Folder 1565)
    - Notebooks: Journals "Three" and "Four", undated (Box 157, Folder 1566)
    - Notebook: Latin. Upper Sixth. Exercises, undated (Box 157, Folder 1567)
    - Notebook: Latin. Upper Sixth. Livy translations, undated (Box 157, Folder 1568)
    - Notebook: Malayan Journal Volume 4, undated (Box 157, Folder 1569)
    - Notebook: "Malayan Journal, Volume Five, Interlude in Bangkok", undated (Box 157, Folder 1570)
    - Notebook: "A Nativity", undated (Box 157, Folder 1571)
    - Notebook: Penang, Chap Goh Meh, February 19-March 7 (Box 157, Folder 1572)
    - Notebook: poems ("NYU"), undated (Box 157, Folder 1573)
    - Notebook: Poems in French, undated (Box 157, Folder 1574)
    - Notebook: Poetry in French, undated (Box 157, Folder 1575)
    - Notebook: "Quotations", undated (Box 158, Folder 1576)
    - Notebook: "Spring customs," etc., undated (Box 158, Folder 1577)
    - Notebook: "The Tokyo Tale", undated (Box 158, Folder 1578)
    - Notebook: Upper Sixth. English Literature., undated (Box 158, Folder 1579)
    - Notebook: Upper Sixth, German notes and vocabulary, undated (Box 158, Folder 1580)
    - "Pages From Notebooks", undated (Box 158, Folder 1581)
  - Reviews by James Kirkup
    Reviews are not arranged in any particular order.
    - Review of How to Go to the Movies by Quentin Crisp, typescript and related material, undated (Box 159, Folder 1582)
    - Review of Whale Nation by Heathcoate Williams, typescript and photocopies, 1988 (Box 159, Folder 1583)
    - Review of The Universal Singular by Pierre Emmanuel, draft, holograph, undated (Box 159, Folder 1584)
    - Reviews for The Listener, holograph, undated (Box 159, Folder 1585)
    - Reviews for Poetry Quarterly, holograph, undated (Box 159, Folder 1586)
    - Reviews and essays, typescripts and clippings, 1957-1971 (Box 159, Folder 1587)
    - "Japanese book reviews," typescripts and clippings, 1980s (Box 159, Folder 1588)
    - Reviews and essays, typescripts and clippings, 1980s (Box 159, Folder 1589-1592)
    - Reviews and essays, typescripts and clippings (continued), 1980s (Box 160, Folder 1593-1595)
    - Reviews and essays ("European"), typescripts and clippings, 1980s (Box 160, Folder 1596-1597)
    - Reviews and essays, typescripts and clippings, 1990s (Box 160, Folder 1598-1599)
    - Reviews and essays, typescripts and clippings (continued), 1990s (Box 161, Folder 1600-1602)
  - Unidentified and Unsorted Writings
    Arranged roughly chronologically
    - "Bits and pieces", 1957 (Box 162, Folder 1603)
    - Poems, drafts, holograph, 1950s, 1973 (Box 162, Folder 1604-1606)
    - Unsorted "scraps", 1940s-1990s (Box 162, Folder 1607-1610)
    - Drafts of translations, 1980s (Box 162, Folder 1611-1612)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings, 1990s (Box 162, Folder 1613-1614)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings (continued), 1990s (Box 163, Folder 1615-1623)
    - Rough drafts and typescripts, signed, 1990s (Box 164, Folder 1624-1626)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings, 2000s (Box 164, Folder 1627-1630)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings (continued), 2000s (Box 165, Folder 1631-1637)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings, 2003-2004 (Box 166, Folder 1638-1642)
    - Drafts of translations, 2000s (Box 166, Folder 1643-1645)
    - Drafts of translations (continued), 2000s (Box 167, Folder 1646-1650)
    - Draft of poems, 2000s (Box 167, Folder 1651-1653)
    - Unsorted writings including notes, drafts and clippings, undated (Box 168, Folder 1654-1659)
    - Reproduction of Rimbaud manuscript "A la Musique", undated (Box 168, Folder 1660)
    - Book jackets for various of James Kirkup's works, 1950s-1970s (Box 168, Folder 1661)
  - Writings of Others
    - Burnett, David. Works of literary criticism, typescripts (copies), 1993-1994, undated (Box 169, Folder 1662-1664)
    - Durrans, Brian. Articles (copies), 1990s (Box 169, Folder 1665)
    - Flower, Dorothy A. A Study of Selected Works of James Kirkup, typescript carbon, 1966 (Box 169, Folder 1666)
    - Garner, David. Five Haiku by the Poet Nozaki. For Soprano and Baritone With Piano Accompaniment, printed version, 1997 (Box 169, Folder 1667)
    - Hall, John Whitney, Japanese History, printed version (copy), undated (Box 169, Folder 1668)
    - Nakagawa, Atsuo. "James Kirkup's Haiku-like Monostiches," copy of printed version, undated (Box 169, Folder 1669)
    - Paul, David
      - The Immoral Gods, typescript, 1991 (Box 169, Folder 1670)
      - Excerpts from notebooks, typescript (copy), undated (Box 169, Folder 1671)
      - Reviews and writings, printed versions (copies), undated (Box 169, Folder 1672)
    - Shoten, Kirihara, Oh My Word!, undated (Box 169, Folder 1673)
    - Smither, Elizabeth, A Pattern of Marching, printed version, accompanied by a letter, 1990 (Box 169, Folder 1674)
    - Takemoto, Akiko, James Kirkup's Poems in Anthologies, typescript and associated material, undated (Box 169, Folder 1675)
    - Teed, Roy. Musical adaptations of James Kirkup poetry, drafts, printed versions and related material, 2000s (Box 170, Folder 1676-1678)
    - Wahrenby, Gun. Poems, typescript, 1988 (Box 170, Folder 1679)
    - Yamaguchi, Seishi. The Essence of Modern Haiku, proof and related correspondence, 1992
    - Yamaguchi, Takeyoshi
      - "A Preliminary Checklist of the Writings of James Kirkup," notes, typescripts, and printed version, 1978 (Box 170, Folder 1680-1682)
      - "A Preliminary Checklist of the Writings of James Kirkup," notes, typescripts, and printed version (continued), 1978 (Box 171, Folder 1683-1688)
      - Title index of James Kirkup's poems, 1971 (Box 171, Folder 1689)
- Personal Papers and Memorabilia, circa 1920-1997; Series III; 1.67; (5 boxes)
  Files are grouped together by type of material but are otherwise unarranged.
  Personal Papers and Memorabilia (Series III) consists of files related to Kirkup's family history, certificates, awards and other objects of memorabilia, financial documents and educational records.
  - Family history files, 1920s-1990s (Box 172, Folder 1690-1692)
  - "Several locks of my hair", undated (Box 172, Folder 1693)
  - Japan Festival Fund Award, 1997
  - Premio Internazionale di Poesia, medal, 1980 (Box 172, Folder 1694)
  - Certificate, Order of Bards Ovates & Druids, 1974 (Box 172, Folder 1695)
  - Certificates, World Academy of Arts and Culture, 1984
  - Wooden sign reading, "All the world's a little queer except thee and me, and even thee's a little queer.", undated (Box 172, Folder 1696)
  - Copyright documents, U.S.A. extension, 1987 (Box 172, Folder 1697)
  - Financial records, 1996-1997 (Box 172, Folder 1698)
  - Housing documents, 1950s-1960s (Box 172, Folder 1699)
  - Birthdate research and horoscopes, 1983, undated (Box 173, Folder 1700-1701)
  - Personal and school documents, including a hymn book, 1930s (Box 173, Folder 1702-1703)
  - Documents and correspondence related to pacifist and socialist organizations, 1940s (Box 173, Folder 1704)
  - Passport, 1946 (Box 173, Folder 1705)
  - Documents relating to travel in Russia, 1970s (Box 173, Folder 1706)
  - University Papers, undated (Box 173, Folder 1707-1709)
  - School Certification Papers and other University Documents, 1940s? (Box 174, Folder 1710-1713)
  - Scroll, in Japanese, undated (Box 175)
  - Metal box engraved with a scene of a boat, undated (Box 176)
- Audiovisual Material, 1993-2002, undated; Series IV; 1.33; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual material in Series IV is restricted pending reformatting. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
  Audiovisual material (Series IV) consists of recordings of James Kirkup reading his poetry, video tapes about or relating to James Kirkup, and two unidentified video recordings in Japanese.
  - Audio tapes of Kirkup reading his works, undated; 3 reel-to-reel audio tapes (Box 177, Folder 1714-1716)
  - Audio tapes of Kirkup reading his works, undated; 10 audio cassettes (Box 177, Folder 1717-1721)
  - Audio tape, lecture by James Kirkup, "where Takemoto-san was present", 1966; 1 reel-to-reel audio tape (Box 177, Folder 1722)
  - Audio tape, Kirkup reading Shakespeare's Macbeth, undated; 1 reel-to-reel audio tape (Box 177, Folder 1723)
  - Audio tape: "Unwritten Law" by Rib Davis, Programme 1, A Case of Blasphemous Obscenity, undated; 1 audio cassette (Box 177, Folder 1724)
  - Video tape: Taboo Programme 4: "No Offence", undated; 1 VHS cassette (Box 177, Folder 1725)
  - Video tape: "Una Mostra Exilografica", undated; 1 VHS cassette (Box 177, Folder 1726)
  - James Kirkup reading at Brighton with et cetera poets, undated; 1 VHS cassette (Box 178, Folder 1727)
  - First International Tanka Contest, 1999 May 2; 1 VHS cassette (Box 178, Folder 1728)
  - Fourth International Tanka Contest, 2002 June 8; 1 VHS cassette (Box 178, Folder 1729)
  - I Love Our Town (filmed in 1972), 1993; 1 VHS cassette (Box 178, Folder 1730)
  - Meditations, 1995; 2 VHS cassettes (Box 178, Folder 1731)
  - Video tapes labeled in Japanese, 1997, undated; 2 VHS cassettes (Box 178, Folder 1732-1733)
- Visual Material, late 1800s-2000s; Series V; 2.29; (6 boxes)
  Nitrate and/or acetate negatives are stored in Restricted Fragile and may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator.
  Organized into two subseries: Photographs and Other Visual Material.
  Visual Material (Series V) consists of photographs, drawings, paintings, and collages. Photographs, which include some duplicates and negatives in addition to original prints, consist of snapshots and portraits of James Kirkup (from boyhood to adulthood), family photographs, and other photographs that Kirkup collected for his publications.
  - Photographs
    Photographs are arranged roughly by date. Since most photographs are undated, the archivist assigned approximate dates by decade.
    - Two views of Old Mundesley, undated (Box 179, Folder 1734)
    - Views of a rural scene in England (South Shields?), undated (Box 179, Folder 1735)